Subtitles brought to you by: The Gone with the Shirt Team @ Viki
Sparrow
- Episode 1 -
1941 Winter, Shanghai had already fallen into enemy hands.
From the outside, it still looked extravagant and well off.
But under the peaceful exterior,
the Japanese special forces had already taken control of the entire Reorganized National Government's Special Operations Division,
wildly arresting and killing anti-Japanese rebels.
The leaders, the anti-Japanese Chinese military men, of our political party
were on the front lines fighting a bloody battle.
At the same time, intelligence agents were sent out to infiltrate the enemy's heart,
starting the underground fight.
Both forces gambled with life and death.
Everywhere there was danger. Every step with the intention to kill.
At Shanghai Bund, the war for spy information
magnificently opened its prologue.
The scene about the secret fight to protect one's country
passionately started.
[Two hours before]
Go to the bulletin board of Liudadai Market
and post this missing person poster.
[An Liusan: member of the Underground Communist Organization]
Sparrow must fly again.
[Missing Person Ad: Su Yanyan, female, 30 years old, average body build...]
[Liu Erbao: Reorganized National Government special agent]
It's him.
Capture him!
[Reorganized National Government of China Special Operations Division of Shanghai]
An Liusan, you're not going to confess?
[Chen Shen: Team Leader of Special Operations Team 1]
Leader Chen!
Your earrings are so pretty, Li Li.
You just chose well!
Cathy, your hair is an inch longer. If you cut it, it'd look perfect.
I was just waiting for you to come and cut it for me!
Later, we'll be opening a function room upstairs waiting for you.
Okay!
You must come!
I will definitely come!
We'll be leaving first!
You don't really think you're popular, do you?
What they like is the money I carry.
Can they find a second fool that would let them spend money like this?
You should only treat one woman well.
We'll talk when I find her.
Don't continue searching, I'm right here!
[Li Xiaonan: Celebrity Company's actress]You should watch yourself, brother.
I don't want you to be my brother! I want to be your wife!
Leader Chen has come!
[Bi Zhongliang: Special Operations Division Chief]
Buddha said that if I don't enter Hell, who will enter Hell?
You're currently still in purgatory. Can your communist belief really save you?
Kill me!
You're right.
What difference is there between the world and the underworld now?
You want to die and be reborn quickly.
But have you thought about your wife and son?
I just hope that you can think it through clearly.
Do you hope that they'll die with you
or live with you?
♫ Rose, Rose, so stunning! ♫
♫ Rose, Rose, so ravishing! ♫
♫ You open in late summer on a tip of a branch.  ♫
♫ Rose, Rose, I love you! ♫
♫  I pledge my heart, my tender love. ♫
♫ Your pure brilliance radiates the whole world. ♫
♫ I pledge my heart, my tender love.  ♫
♫ Your pure radiance illuminates the world. ♫
♫ Rose, Rose, your limbs so slender,  ♫
♫ Rose, Rose, your thorns so sharp. ♫
♫  Today's stormy rains may ravage you, bruising your limbs and graceful body.  ♫
♫  Rose, Rose, I love you! ♫
Miss, are you alone?
I'm never alone.
Miss, can I have a dance?
- Sorry-- Go on, I'll get some rest.
Bye.
This dance isn't done yet!
Miss, just give me some respect.
Vodka is too strong. It doesn't suit a lady like you.
Tom, give her one bottle of Kvass.
Okay, Mr. Chen.
- Will you also drink Kvass?- Right.
Thank you.
It looks like you are a player who likes parties.
I don't like to drink. I only drink this type.
I'm not a player either.
Maybe I'm getting old. I don't even have the energy to play around.
Then why are you still smoking
the Japanese's Sakura cigarettes?
Because this matches my identity as a Chinese traitor.
Chief, he signed it.
Chief, this Sparrow!
This Sparrow finally landed in our net.
The Heavens are really rewarding us food to eat.
- Call Chen Shen back for me.- Yes, sir.
I'm Prime Minister.
I didn't think that it'd be you...
Sister-in-Law.
Chen Shen, you've suffered.
I'm not suffering.
After my brother sacrificed himself,
I've been looking all over for you.
I've been looking for Pi Pi.
I'm alone in Shanghai.
I'm like a wandering ghost.
I know.
Division Chief, Special Operations Team 1 has completed our preparations. We are ready for your orders.
Where is your team leader?
Our leader...
We didn't find him. Did he take a day off?
Who did he take leave with? Why don't I know about it?
I can't ever stop worrying about him.
Good sign. Set out to Mee Koo May.
Listen to my order!
Everyone, turn left!
Run forward!
Get into the car.
In these three years, where did you two go?
Shen Hai told me to tell you one thing:
Silence is for one to have a better chance to explode.
You didn't receive any contact for these three years so you could hide deeper,
but the organization has always been concerned about you.
Three years.
What did I do for these three years? I only waited every day.
I spent my time around red party lights, green wines, food, and playing!
Like a walking corpse.
I know.
It's been difficult for you these three years.
I promised my brother. I would definitely protect you well.
I'll take you away from Shanghai to Yan'an.
We want to go, too, but we cannot go.
- We are people with missions.- I know. I'm not afraid of death!
I know we have a mission. Before we kick out the Japanese,
we cannot live peacefully.
But these days have been too hard for me.
I live every day among the Japanese and Chinese traitors.
I cannot beat them or kill them, I can only laugh with them!
Is this the way humans should live?
There's little time, let's talk about serious matters.
Is there any new situation happening at the Special Operations Division?
There were a lot of intelligence reports about Sparrow recently.
It's giving the Japanese a headache. They've given the Special Operations a deadline to catch him.
Do you know about a top secret military plan of the Japanese?
What's the code name?
According to the latest intelligence that our organization got,
The Reorganized National Government and the Japanese have built a secret base.
The special spy agents that were trained from this base
will then be ordered to infiltrate the communist and nationalist militaries.
They will try to infiltrate deeply and
aim to destroy our parties from within.
Once their plan succeeds, it will cause a disastrous effect.
We still don't know the code name of this plan.
It must not have yet involved our operation division.
That's why I hope that you can find it soon.
This is a top secret plan of the Japanese army to destroy China.
You must grab hold of the plan's code name and details then report it to our party leaders.
Sister-in-Law, is Pi Pi doing well?
He's doing quite good. Don't worry.
Can I go see Pi Pi?
Right now, Pi Pi is not by my side,
but he's in a very safe place.
It's just that you can't go see him.
So as not to let the enemy suspect you, to protect your identity.
This is the party's rules.
Then how do I contact you in the future?
There's a church on Doule Road
called Hongde Church. Beside it, there's a mailbox.
I know that place.
Write on the letter: No. 79 Ningde Road, to Mr. Gan Daofu.
Your superior will then inform me about your news.
That person's code name is Doctor.
Is that mailbox safe?
Very safe. The mailman on that road belongs to our party.
Chen Shen, from this day on,
your code number is 023.
I'll get going.
Sister-in-Law,
I'll leave first.
Be careful.
Timing And Subtitles Brought To You By The Gone With The Shirt Team @ Viki
Division Chief...
The snow this year came very early.
Hey, you guys, follow me closely later.
Go! Go.
Rock, paper, scissors!
You lost. You lost.
I'll drink. I'll drink. I'll drink.
Xiaonan, what film are you shooting recently?
Recently,
with some Director Zheng Zhengqiu and a lot more.
I'm currently choosing scripts
to see which role is more suitable for me.
If you really became a celebrity, don't forget us.
- I will surely not forget you guys. I'll treat you guys to wine by then.- You just had a few lines on your last movie and now there are already directors competing for you?
You really got famous quickly.
That's right. Soon, I'll already be a big celebrity.
Why were you gone for so long?
- Come. Let's play a game.- I don't want to play.
Hey, Mister, Kvass, right?
Don't want to play and don't want to drink alcohol, how are you like a man?
Then how come you still like me?
I just like you.
Hurry up all of you! Hurry up!
Stop right there.
Is there anything you need?
Come down.
Stop! Don't move!
Don't shoot!
- Catch her alive.- Chase!
Chase!
Don't run! Don't run!
After her!
- The rest of you come with me!- Yes!
Hurry! Let's go! Let's go! Hurry! Go!
Stop! Don't run! Stop right there!
Stop right there!
Surround her! Don't move! Don't move!
Don't move! Don't move! Don't move!
Who told you to open fire? Who told you to shoot?!
- I told you guys to catch her alive! Don't you understand that?!- Put it down. Put it down.
- Take her to Tongren Hospital! Hurry!- Hurry! Hurry!
- No one should leave the night club!- Yes! Let's go.
All of you, go back inside! Go back in!
Ms. Li... Ms. Li...
All of you go in! Hurry!
Deringer, pocket-sized Browning. This is a rare gun.
Today, you're on duty but you're not at the division headquarters. Why did you appear here?
It's as if you don't know. I frequently go off post.
You're becoming more and more unreasonable!
You want me to report it to Li Moqun like that, right?
You don't want this job anymore, is that right?
Just tell him that I came here first to lead the squad.
Is she a communist or a nationalist?
Come inside with me.
The happiness of reuniting with one's family hasn't dissipated yet,
but unexpected changes just happened right in front of him.
Chen Shen told himself
that the real trial has arrived.
While praying that his sister-in-law can survive,
he tells himself that
at this time, he must not show
even a bit of a mistake.
Or else, he and Prime Minister
will all fall into a desperate situation.
Among all of you,
who else knows that lady from earlier?
You, little flat head, come out.
He's talking about you. Come out.
I don't know her. I really don't know her.
- Come out!- I only said one sentence.
All of you have already been registered in our records.
When we need you, you must come anytime when called.
Do you hear me?
We heard you.
I didn't hear it clearly.
I can't drink this.
Why can't you drink it?
It's too unsophisticated.
So the sodas you drink are sophisticated?
Drinking them during winter makes your body shiver.
Stop pretending here.
If I don't pretend, how will the women like me?
Then why don't you find a serious one to introduce to me?
Stop looking for bar girls or actresses, okay?
Reporting to Division Chief, everyone has already been inspected.
We've caught 8 suspects.
Don't let anyone off.
Don't worry, Division Chief. Everyone has already been put on record.
Sorry, everyone. We have interfered with your time.
May everyone continue with what you were doing.
Disband the team.
Take all of them back. Take them away.
You're leaving already?
Yeah, we're going.
- Move.- I just went out to have fun and that's illegal?
Everyone tell me. Did I commit anything illegal?!
Did I break the law? Right?
Damn you! I'm going to tell you what law you broke.
Vodka is too strong. It doesn't suit a lady like you.
Tom.
Timings And Subtitles Brought To You By The Gone With The Shirt Team @ Viki
Even though he hasn't slept all night,
even though he's anxiously curious about the state of Shen Qiuxia's injury,
Chen Shen still forcefully pacified himself.
He must act like he used to, enduring until 8:30 AM before leaving his room.
He must pretend not to care about anything.
And every second of waiting, for his current self,
are like years passing by.
Boss!
I'm late. I'm late.
I just came back from the hospital.
I'll first get you some water then I'll go buy your breakfast.
You just came back this morning? Is that person still alive?
Yes. If she died, I would have returned earlier.
Where did that intelligence yesterday come from?
We caught a communist. After torturing him hard, he finally confessed.
Although that woman looked quite refined, she's quite high ranked within the communist organization.
She's called something like... Prime Minister.
That high? She's just one level lower than the emperor.
Right?
That Sparrow that we were looking for is under her.
Think about it, quite high-ranked, right?
High. Really high.
I'll first go get some water then I'll buy you breakfast.
Don't buy breakfast today.
After you're done getting water, go and make up some sleep.
Afterwards, go to the hospital to continue keeping watch.
- I'll go eat breakfast by myself.- Don't...
The money is already with me. I surely have to buy you one.
When have I inquired about how you spend my money?
I also will be eating.
I'll buy one back for you. Okay?
That's not suitable. This...
It's settled already.
Then I... want to eat pan fried pork bun.
It was tiring for you to be on night duty.
Even if you don't say it, I'll buy you a pan fired pork bun.
Thank you, Boss.
I'll go get water now.
Is this Fushou Cigarette Shop?
Hello.
All eight have already confessed?
Okay. I'll be there later to personally interrogate them.
Wu Zhiguo!
- Hurry and get Chen Shen for me.- Yes.
Jeez, Leader Chen, you're finally here.
Look how long my bangs are. It's blocking my eyes already. Cut them for me later.
No problem. To be able to serve a beautiful lady is exactly what I've been looking for.
I'll help you after I've eaten breakfast.
Leader Chen's tongue is really so sweet.
Say, which woman won't be enchanted to death by you?
Beautiful ladies only say it
but not one is willing to marry me.
Oh, right. I heard that you guys caught a lot of communists.
Your news is quite up-to-date.
Everyone already knew upon arriving this morning.
One communist is in the hospital while the other eight have already confessed.
That's right. Old Bi's headache will start now.
Leader Chen, Division Chief asked you to go to him.
Oh, I got it.
I'll go see Old Bi first. I'll cut your hair afterwards.
Let's cover it or else it would be cold later.
Is there a suspect that needs a haircut?
Other than knowing to cut hair and looking for girls, what else do you know to do?
Oh. Does gambling count?
Stop acting silly.
During usual days, it's fine but today we have serious matters to attend to.
Be a little serious. You're a team leader after all.
Team Leader Chen.
Say it.
Just randomly pick one then just eliminate the other seven.
Done?
You watched for so long and you can only tell me this?
Do I need you to teach me that?
I have no way to look at it. Unless you want to investigate each of their backgrounds thoroughly.
Just talking to her makes them her communist comrades? I've even talked with her.
You even talked with her?
I even treated her to a soda.
She's quite pretty. Isn't she?
What did you say?
Miss, do you want a haircut?
Director Jiang should really be embarrassed to have an instructor like you for the Batch 16 of the Whampoa Military Academy.
That's why I don't brag around that I'm from Whampoa Military Academy.
I just tell them that I'm from the 66th Revolutionary Army
and was just a cook.
Get lost. Get lost.
Let me say another thing. Okay?
Are you sure that woman is a communist?
The communist we caught beforehand, An Liusan, has already went to the hospital to take a look.
It's her.
Do you want to call Special Operations Team 2 to help?
Go then.
At the hospital, once her situation even slightly improves,
bring her back here.
- I'm going now.- Go then.
Division Chief,
are you suspecting Team Leader Chen?
Later, bring out that flat headed guy to me.
- I'm going to personally interrogate him.- Yes.
Tell Wu Zhiguo to go to the hospital and keep watch of Chen Shen.
I understand.
Don't ever let Chen Shen and the suspect have any chance to interact with each other.
Yes.
- Boss.- Boss.
Team 1 will take care of the inside while Team 2 will handle the outside.
Yes, Team Leader Chen.
Let's go.
Come. Come. Come. Hurry and follow.
[Wu Zhiguo: Special Operations Team 2, deputy team leader]
Do you guys know what a big fish is? If a lured fish escapes,
- we will be killed.- Yes, sir.
Guard closely.
Boss.
How is it?
It's one steel tube. All the guards inside and outside are our men.
Other than the suspect, are there other patients here?
Last night, they transferred two patients inside.
They're both about to die. I've already informed the hospital about our situation.
Even families of the patients can't get in easily.
How many exits are there inside?
Just this one.
Then is the suspect awake already?
She's already awake. She's even more energetic than me.
Hey, Old Bi said that as long as she's not dying, we're taking her back for interrogation.
That's great. Let's hurry and take her back.
Our men wouldn't even dare to close their eyes, afraid that we'll lose her.
- What room is the suspect in?- 322.
322...
Bian Tou!
- What's the situation of the suspect?- I've already reported it to Boss.
Oh, Team Leader Chen.
Team Leader Chen.
Let's go. Let's go to her room and see.
Doctor, how's the suspect's injuries?
The bullet penetrated through her right shoulder but it didn't injure the lungs.
She most likely isn't in any life-threatening danger.
Sterilization, hemostasis, and surgery for infection.
You have not done any of these yet?
Right. We must first sterilize the wound
and observe the situation.
We're still discussing about it.
Based on her current state,
if she can recuperate well, she'll be able to get out of bed very soon.
Our operation headquarters also has a medical clinic.
Prescribe all the medicines that she'll need.
We will be taking the suspect back for interrogation.
This... What if her wounds get infected?
Team Leader Chen, Division Chief Bi has already given instructions that as long as the suspect is not dying,
then we must immediately take her back for interrogation.
Old Bi also said the same thing to me.
Then may I ask Team Leader Chen to call Division Chief Bi to clarify our next move?
Okay. Where's the phone?
- I have one in my office.- Lead the way.
It's the clinic in the room across from here. Let's go.
Is this Fushou Cigarette Shop? I'm looking for Pi Dan.
Brother Shen, here's the stuff that you asked for.
Just this much, will it work?
It's so effective. Be careful not to hurt yourself.
No one knows about this thing, right?
No one. How will anyone know?
I'll go now.
Shen Zhaoqing,
you've already confessed to everything. Do you know that it's a crime punishable by death?
I know.
Think about if you still have anything you want to tell me
that might save your life.
I really just told that woman one statement.
If talking is punishable by death,
that person earlier told her more than one sentence.
I really am innocent.
Did you hear what they were talking about?
I also didn't clearly hear it. I just remember that
he ordered a bottle of Kvass for that lady.
Reporting, Division Chief!
Team Leader Chen has called from the hospital.
Hello.
The bullet penetrated through soft tissues. It didn't injure the lungs.
She broke a rib and is still lying down here in the hospital.
Do you want to come over and take a look?
Okay. I'll go over there to take a look.
Hurry up.
Come in.
Division Chief, will you be continuing to interrogate that Shen Zhaoqing?
He came to Shanghai from Chongqing (Nationalist headquarters) last month, right?
Right. That's what he said.
- Send some men to investigate his background at Chongqing.- Yes.
- Prepare the car. To Tongren Hospital.- Yes.
Subtitles and Timing brought to you by the Gone With The Shirt Team @ Viki
♫ Fly, fly towards the bright light. ♫
♫ Fly past the endless confusion. ♫
♫ At worst, you’ll hurt your wings. ♫
♫ At least you’ll still have some remaining hope. ♫
♫ Fly, fly towards the sun, ♫
♫ even if your ultimate destination is death. ♫
♫ At worst, you’ll lose your clothes. ♫
♫ At least you’ll still have your original faith. ♫
♫ I shake off the bitter cold in my body. I only want to rest in your harbor. ♫
♫ You should know that this is the biggest longing in my life. ♫
♫ But my home is in devastation. I can’t cower to safety. ♫
♫ Forgive me. Allow my last rallying cry. ♫
♫ I will become brave, bravely breaking through the prison bars. ♫
♫ The distant road is long. ♫
♫ For freedom, I am willing to be pierced through the chest. ♫
♫ I have already become brave, bravely charging into the darkness. ♫
♫ The dimming fire and lights of home in the distance ♫
♫ is my ultimate faith. ♫